# Johnbosco **Tayebwa**

#### **BIOINFORMATICIAN**

School of Allied Health Sciences, Kampala International University (KIU), Uganda

□+256 784362367 | ☑ johnboscotayebwa@kiu.ac.ug | ☑ 0000-0002-2355-8475 | ☑ biocodebreaker | ὧ Johnbosco

Tayebwa



Research Focus: My broad interest is integrating various high-dimensional omics datasets such as genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, metabolomics etc to develop personalized immunotherapy approaches for cancer patients. I am also interested in the application of Single-Cell RNA-Seq for personalized immunotherapy. My Research Focus area is Cancer Immunotherapy especially immune cell infiltration in the Tumor Microenvironment (TME). I am also interested in using Al/ML for computational modeling to develop better prognostic models for Cancer patients. This includes biomarker discovery.

## **Education**

#### Master of Science in Bioinformatics

2011-2012 Sweden

University of Skovde

Bachelor of Biomedical Laboratory Technology, Second Class Honours - Upper Division

2005-2008

MAKERERE UNIVERSITY

Uganda

# Professional Experience

#### **Assistant Lecturer/Research Scientist**

SCHOOL OF ALLIED HEALTH SCIENCES, KAMPALA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Current

Uganda

#### **Head of Department**

DEPARTMENT OF MEDICAL LABORATORY SCIENCES, KAMPALA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

2021-2023

Uganda

#### Bioinformatician

DEPARTMENT OF CLINICAL GENETICS, LUND UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL

2012-2014

• Sweden

#### **Visiting Postgraduate Researcher**

School of Biosciences, University of Exeter

2010-2011

• United Kingdom

## Skills\_

#### PROGRAMMING

• Advanced skills in Linux-Unix bash/shell, R statistical programming, GitHub and Perl

#### HIGH PERFORMANCE COMPUTING

• Experience with HPC clusters (UPPMAX, SNIC) and cloud computing (Amazon AWS, docker)

#### NGS DATA ANALYSIS

• More than 5 years of experience in management and analysis of high-throughput data from Next-Generation Sequencing Platforms, especially Illumina

• Experience with gene expression array and microarray (SNP-array) data analysis

## **Research Experience**

#### **Department of Clinical Genetics, Lund University Hospital**

BIOINFORMATICIAN 2012-201

 Analyzed NGS data (WGS, WES, TruSeq, RNA-Seq) for bone and soft tissue tumor studies. Developed pipelines for variant calling, fusion gene detection, and differential expression analysis.

#### **School of Biosciences, University of Exeter**

VISITING POSTGRADUATE RESEARCHER

2010-2011

 Developed competence in Linux environment and Perl scripting. Assembled bacterial genomes and developed in-silico primers for Xanthomonas species.

## Selected Publications

I have a dozen publications including one where I'm First Author (shared), one in *Nature Genetics*, and a Review Article on the Methods used in Cancer Research.

For a complete list of publications, please visit: Google Scholar Profile.

# Professional Membership \_\_\_\_\_

Member of the International Society for Computational Biology (ISCB)

## **Honors & Awards**

#### Top 500 Scientists in Uganda - AD Scientific Index

POSITION 136 IN UGANDA; POSITION 16 AT KIU; CATEGORY: DIGITAL HEALTH TECHNOLOGIES | HEALTH INFORMATICS

2022

#### **Swedish Institute Scholarship**

Swedish Institute 2011-2012

#### **Millennium Science Initiative Research Grant**

NARO/WORLD BANK PROJECT 2010-2011

#### Muljibhai Madhvani Foundation scholarship

MULJIBHAI MADHVANI FOUNDATION 2006-2008

#### References\_\_\_

#### 1. Anthony Mukwaya, PhD

Research Scientist/Research Fellow

Department of Ophthalmology, Harvard Medical School

Schepens Eye Research Institute, Boston, MA, USA

Email: amukwaya@meei.harvard.edu

Tel: +1 617 4609884

#### 2. David Studholme, PhD

Associate Professor in Bioinformatics

School of Biosciences, University of Exeter

Exeter, UK

Email: D.J.Studholme@exeter.ac.uk

**Tel:** +44 (0) 1392 724678

#### 3. Fredrik Mertens, MD, PhD

Professor, Senior Consultant Department of Clinical Genetics, University Hospital Lund, Sweden

Email: Fredrik.Mertens@med.lu.se

**Tel:** 0046 46 173387